Guide to the Charles James Hendley Papers TAM.109
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series V: Subject Files, 1914-1962; 309693
  - Various Teacher Unions, State Level: Minnesota State Federation of Teachers (AFT), 1939, 1940; 310273 (Box 17, Folder 42)
  - Various Teacher Union Locals (AFT), 1937-1939 (Box 17, Folder 43)
  - Various Teacher Union Locals (ATF), 1940 (Box 17, Folder 44)
  - Various Teacher Unions, State Level: New Jersey Federation of Teachers (AFT), 1938-1944; 310274 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Various Teacher Unions, State Level: Wisconsin State Federation of Teachers (AFT), 1938, 1941; 310275 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Veblen College, [1937]; 310276 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Walden School, 1940, undated; 310277 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Wallace, Henry A.: Presidential Campaign, 1947-1948; 310278 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Washington Square College of Arts and Sciences: Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1952; 310279 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - "Why the CIO Opened the Food Store", 1948; 310280 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Woll, Matthew, [1940]; 310281 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - The Worker, 1946-1962, undated; 310282 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - The Worker: Correspondence, 1951-1962, undated; 310283 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - The Worker: Financial and Other Administrative Materials, including Meeting Minutes, 1952-1958, 1960-1961; 310284 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - The Worker: Hendley Appearances before Internal Security Committee of the US Senate (1952) and Grand Jury (1962) regarding The Worker, 1952, 1961-1962; 310285 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - The Worker: May Day, 1953-1961; 310286 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Worker Education, 1925-1939, undated; 310287 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - World War II Materials, 1942, undated; 310288 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Youth: Various Issues, 1926, 1939-1947, 1960, undated; 310289 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Zorach, Tessim and Esta Gluck v. Andrew G. Clausen et al. (Supreme Court of the State of New York): Brief, [1951]; 310290 (Box 18, Folder 17)
- Series VI: Photographs, 1913-1959; 498212
  This series contains fifty black and white photographs, many of which are portraits of Hendley. The earliest is a 1913 photograph of Hendley and a group of students at a school in Monroe, North Carolina where he was a faculty member. Approximately twenty additional portraits depict Hendley throughout his life. A variety of Teachers Union events are also documented, including an Educational Conference, a 25th Anniversary gathering and a May Day Parade.
  - Hendley: Portrait, 1913; 498213 (Box A006, Folder 1)
  - Hendley: Portraits, 1940s; 498214 (Box A006, Folder 2)
  - Hendley: Portraits, 1950s; 498215 (Box A006, Folder 3)
  - Hendley: Portraits, undated; 498216 (Box A006, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous, undated; 498217 (Box A006, Folder 5)
  - Teachers Union: 23rd Annual Educational Conference, 1959; 498218 (Box A006, Folder 6)
  - Teachers Union: 25th Anniversary, Jun 1941; 498219 (Box A006, Folder 7)
  - Teachers Union: May Day Parade, 1937; 498220 (Box A006, Folder 8)
  - Unidentified Parade (Oversize), [1940s]; 498221 (Box OS008, Folder 1)